<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-05T16:15:09-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">kahveci group</title><subtitle>Your Site Description</subtitle><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Request for Letter of Recommendation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/xxz" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Request for Letter of Recommendation" /><published>2020-08-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/xxz</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/xxz">&lt;p&gt;Excellent students who have worked in my research group and who have received a high grade in my classes will be able to ask for recommendation letters for graduate school, medical school, or other future employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important note that it is to your advantage to ask for recommendation letters from faculty who know you well outside of the classroom. If you were a student in my class and not a member of my research group, it is usually more appropriate to ask another faculty for a recommendation letter. That way, they can state specific information about your qualifications and experiences that is not already presented on your transcript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please follow these specific guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email me as soon as possible to ask for a recommendation letter and to schedule a meeting to discuss your future career plans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is my policy to only write letters for students who waive their rights to read the letters of recommendation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit your materials in person at least 1 month before the due date. The earlier you can give me your application materials, the more time I will have to work on your recommendation letters.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A short typed paragraph on our previous interactions at DePaul University
(e.g., in which of my classes you were in and your grade in each class, what quarters you were involved in my research group and what specific work you did, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Any necessary forms from each graduate school (with as much information filled out on the form as possible).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Addressed and stamped envelopes for each application. Please be sure to include the return address as well:
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Murat Kahveci&lt;br /&gt;
Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry DePaul University&lt;br /&gt;
1110 W. Belden Ave., 100A McGowan South&lt;br /&gt; 
Chicago, IL 60614&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A copy of your vita or resume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A copy of your personal statement.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A document containing your GPA, Chemistry GPA, GRE score, previous research experience, specific future career plans, specific research interests you hope to pursue in graduate school or medical school, and any other relevant information about you and your academic accomplishments.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Please send me an email (in addition to a printed out a list) with a PDF Document that contains all of the addresses, specific graduate or medical schools, and the due dates for each application.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After the application process is finished, please email me and let me know what graduate programs or medical schools you have been accepted to and which program you have selected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep in touch and let me know how much fun you’re having in graduate or medical school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="My Students" /><summary type="html">Excellent students who have worked in my research group and who have received a high grade in my classes will be able to ask for recommendation letters for graduate school, medical school, or other future employers. Important note that it is to your advantage to ask for recommendation letters from faculty who know you well outside of the classroom. If you were a student in my class and not a member of my research group, it is usually more appropriate to ask another faculty for a recommendation letter. That way, they can state specific information about your qualifications and experiences that is not already presented on your transcript. Please follow these specific guidelines: Email me as soon as possible to ask for a recommendation letter and to schedule a meeting to discuss your future career plans. It is my policy to only write letters for students who waive their rights to read the letters of recommendation. Submit your materials in person at least 1 month before the due date. The earlier you can give me your application materials, the more time I will have to work on your recommendation letters. A short typed paragraph on our previous interactions at DePaul University (e.g., in which of my classes you were in and your grade in each class, what quarters you were involved in my research group and what specific work you did, etc.) Any necessary forms from each graduate school (with as much information filled out on the form as possible). Addressed and stamped envelopes for each application. Please be sure to include the return address as well: Murat Kahveci Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry DePaul University 1110 W. Belden Ave., 100A McGowan South Chicago, IL 60614 A copy of your vita or resume. A copy of your personal statement. A document containing your GPA, Chemistry GPA, GRE score, previous research experience, specific future career plans, specific research interests you hope to pursue in graduate school or medical school, and any other relevant information about you and your academic accomplishments. Please send me an email (in addition to a printed out a list) with a PDF Document that contains all of the addresses, specific graduate or medical schools, and the due dates for each application. After the application process is finished, please email me and let me know what graduate programs or medical schools you have been accepted to and which program you have selected. Keep in touch and let me know how much fun you’re having in graduate or medical school.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Acids and Bases Experiment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hba" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Acids and Bases Experiment" /><published>2020-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hba</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hba">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button button--outline-success button--pill button--xs&quot; href=&quot;/tpv&quot;&gt;CHE 139&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext success highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Experiment 5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#goals&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#examine-the-effect-of-dilution-on-the-ph-of-strong-and-weak-acids-and-bases&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-examine-the-effect-of-dilution-on-the-ph-of-strong-and-weak-acids-and-bases&quot;&gt;Examine the effect of dilution on the pH of strong and weak acids and bases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#calculating-the-values-of-k_a-and-k_b&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-calculating-the-values-of-k_a-and-k_b&quot;&gt;Calculating the values of \(K_a\) and \(K_b\)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#examine-the-ph-of-mixtures-of-strong-and-weak-acids-and-bases&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-examine-the-ph-of-mixtures-of-strong-and-weak-acids-and-bases&quot;&gt;Examine the pH of mixtures of strong and weak acids and bases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#assignment&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#qas&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#calculating-the-concentration-of-110-and-1100-solutions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-calculating-the-concentration-of-110-and-1100-solutions&quot;&gt;Calculating the concentration of 1:10 and 1:100 solutions&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#10-fold-or-110-dilution&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-10-fold-or-110-dilution&quot;&gt;10-fold or 1:10 dilution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#second-10-fold-or-1100-dilution&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-second-10-fold-or-1100-dilution&quot;&gt;Second 10-fold or 1:100 dilution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#volumes-in-l-or-ml-for-dilution-calculations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-volumes-in-l-or-ml-for-dilution-calculations&quot;&gt;Volumes in L or mL for dilution calculations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#team-grading&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;examine-the-effect-of-dilution-on-the-ph-of-strong-and-weak-acids-and-bases&quot;&gt;Examine the effect of dilution on the pH of strong and weak acids and bases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Calculate, using \(M_1V_1 = M_2V_2\), the concentration of HCl, NaOH, CH\(_3\)COOH, and NH\(_4\)OH for the 1:10 and 1:100 diluted solutions and the mixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Calculate \([H_3O^+]\) for each solution using the measured pH values and Equation \(\ref{eq:H3O}\).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:pH}
  pH = - \log [H_3O^+]
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:H3O}
  \text{[H}_3\text{O}^+\text{]} = 10^{-\text{pH}}
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make a plot of pH vs. concentration for HCl and CH\(_3\)COOH, and another for NaOH and NH\(_4\)OH.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The strong and weak species should show a different dependence of pH on concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calculating-the-values-of-k_a-and-k_b&quot;&gt;Calculating the values of \(K_a\) and \(K_b\)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:Ka}
  K_a = \frac{ [A^-][H_3O^+] }{ [HA]}
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where, \([H_2O]\) is omitted because it is pure liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:Kb}
  K_b = \frac{ [BH^+][OH^-] }{ [B] }
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where, \([H_2O]\) is omitted because it is pure liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:percent-ionization-acid}
  \% \text{ ionization} = \frac{ [H_3O^+]}{ [HA]_0} \times 100\% =  \frac{ [A^-] }{ [HA]_0 } \times 100\%
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:percent-ionization-base}
  \% \text{ ionization} = \frac{ [BH^+] }{ [B]_0 } \times 100\% = \frac{ [OH^-] }{ [B]_0 } \times 100\%
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate \(K_a\) using Equation \ref{eq:Ka},&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate \(K_b\) using Equation \ref{eq:Kb},&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the percent dissociation of the weak acid using Equation \ref{eq:percent-ionization-acid}, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the percent dissociation of the weak base using Equation \ref{eq:percent-ionization-base}.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;examine-the-ph-of-mixtures-of-strong-and-weak-acids-and-bases&quot;&gt;Examine the pH of mixtures of strong and weak acids and bases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Examine the pH of mixtures of strong and weak acids and bases to see how the presence of a strong acid or base impacts the percent dissociation of the weak acid or base.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the percent dissociation of the weak acid using Equation \ref{eq:percent-ionization-acid}, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the percent dissociation of the weak base using Equation \ref{eq:percent-ionization-base}.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch pH meter calibration video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch solution preparation and pH determination video
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only shown for HCl; same process used for other solutions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the post-lab quiz with a 70% or higher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the data set and do the data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You must upload a PDF file of &lt;strong&gt;partial lab report&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a deviation for the summer session only&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Include the following sections: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Procedures&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pH Data Tables&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pH vs. Concentration Plots&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/code&gt; (not a full discussion section; just itemize and answer the questions.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You don’t need to include sample calculations in the partial report (it is in Excel only), don’t need to write narrative explaining data tables and calculations.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You must upload all calculations and data tables in an MS Excel file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should review the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Lab Report Guidelines&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sample General Chemistry Lab Report&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Appendix E&lt;/code&gt; on D2L while writing to ensure that your drafts are correctly formatted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calculating-the-concentration-of-110-and-1100-solutions&quot;&gt;Calculating the concentration of 1:10 and 1:100 solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think \(V_1\) for stock solutions is 50 mL, but can’t figure out what \(V_1\) is for 1:10 (10 mL ?) and 1:100 dilutions. I want to confirm that \(M_1\) is 1.0 M for all calculations and \(V_2\) is 100 mL. I’ve looked at the lab procedure and lab video, but get confused about the process of dilutions regarding volumes of \(V_1\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, I will walk through the concentration calculations for the  hydrochloric acid dilutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concentration of the stock solution,  \(M_1 = 1.00 \text{ M}\) (let’s use 3 sig. figs.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; means initial state. Likewise,  we would use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; to indicate the final state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;10-fold-or-110-dilution&quot;&gt;10-fold or 1:10 dilution&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Dilute the solution 10-fold by using a clean, primed, 10 mL volumetric pipette to add 10.00 mL of the stock acid solution to a 100 mL volumetric flask and filling it to the line with deionized water.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;\(V_1 = 10.00 \text{ mL}\), which is the amount taken from the stock solution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;\(V_2 = 100.00 \text{ mL}\), final volume after the dilution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calculate the concentration of 10-fold dilution as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

\[M_1 V_1 = M_2 V_2 \notag\]

\[M_2 = \frac{M_1 V_1}{V_2} \notag\]

\[M_2 = \frac{(1.00 \text{ M}) (10.00 \text{ mL})}{100.00 \text{ mL}} \notag\]

\[M_2 = 0.100 \text{ M HCl solution} \notag\]

&lt;h4 id=&quot;second-10-fold-or-1100-dilution&quot;&gt;Second 10-fold or 1:100 dilution&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Dilute this solution [i.e. 10-fold diluted colution] another 10-fold by using a 10 mL volumetric pipette to add 10 mL of the 1:10 acid solution to a 100 mL volumetric flask and filling it to the line with deionized water.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we are using the concentration of 10-fold dilution as the initial concentration for the second 10-fold dilution.&lt;/p&gt;

\[M_2 = \frac{(0.100 \text{ M}) (10.00 \text{ mL})}{100.00 \text{ mL}} \notag\]

\[M_2 = 0.0100 \text{ M HCl solution} \notag\]

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volumes-in-l-or-ml-for-dilution-calculations&quot;&gt;Volumes in L or mL for dilution calculations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I noticed in your sample calculations for the 10 and 100 fold dilutions you used the volumes in mL where molarity is calculated using the units liters. I was wondering if we were to use the volumes in mL as you did in the sample calculations under the Q&amp;amp;A’s or convert these to the units of liters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unit of analysis for volume could be &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mL&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;L&lt;/code&gt; in dilution calculations because the volume units cancel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-mermaid&quot;&gt;  graph LR;
    A[Is the assignment for the Acids and Bases Experiment graded as a team?]
    B[Which sections are graded by the instructor?]
    C[Which sections are graded by the teaching assistant?]

    B1[Overall Clarity and Flow]
    B2[Results]
    B3[Proofreading and General Formatting]
    B4[pH Data Tables]
    B5[pH vs. Concentration Plots]
    B6[Discussion Questions]

    C1[Procedure]
    C2[Table Formatting]
    C3[Figure Formatting]
    C4[Prelab Quiz]
    C5[Postlab Quiz]
    C6[Excel Calculations]

    A--yes--&amp;gt;B;
    A--yes--&amp;gt;C;
    B--&amp;gt;B1;
    B--&amp;gt;B2;
    B--&amp;gt;B3;
    B--&amp;gt;B4;
    B--&amp;gt;B5;
    B--&amp;gt;B6;

    C--&amp;gt;C1;
    C--&amp;gt;C2;
    C--&amp;gt;C3;
    C--&amp;gt;C4;
    C--&amp;gt;C5;
    C--&amp;gt;C6;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions regarding your scores, please let &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mkahveci@depaul.edu&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; or your &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brownt1129@gmail.com&quot;&gt;TA&lt;/a&gt; know.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="SSQ20 CHE 139" /><summary type="html">Goals, assignments, and Q&amp;As about the Acids and Bases Experiment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The KHP Titration Experiment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/von" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The KHP Titration Experiment" /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/von</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/von">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button button--outline-success button--pill button--xs&quot; href=&quot;/tpv&quot;&gt;CHE 139&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext success highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Experiment 4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#goals&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#calculate-the-molarity-of-standardized-naoh&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-calculate-the-molarity-of-standardized-naoh&quot;&gt;Calculate the molarity of standardized NaOH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#calculate-the-mass-of-khp-in-impure-khp&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-calculate-the-mass-of-khp-in-impure-khp&quot;&gt;Calculate the mass of KHP in impure KHP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#assignment&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#qas&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#having-double-burette-readings-for-a-trial&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-having-double-burette-readings-for-a-trial&quot;&gt;Having double burette readings for a trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#team-grading&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calculate-the-molarity-of-standardized-naoh&quot;&gt;Calculate the molarity of standardized NaOH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the moles of KHP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[n_\text{KHP} = \frac{m_\text{pure KHP}}{ 204.2212 ~\text{ g/mol}}\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determine the moles of NaOH using the stoichiometric ratio for the reaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[n_{\text{NaOH}} = n_\text{KHP} \times  \frac{ 1 ~\text{ mol NaOH}}{ 1 ~\text{mol KHP}}\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determine the molarity of NaOH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[M_\text{NaOH} = \frac{ n_{\text{NaOH}}}{ V_{\text{NaOH}}}\]

&lt;p&gt;where \(V_{\text{NaOH}}\) is the volume of NaOH in liters (L) to reach the endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the average molarity of NaOH and its standard deviation. Use the average concentration value for the subsequent calculations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calculate-the-mass-of-khp-in-impure-khp&quot;&gt;Calculate the mass of KHP in impure KHP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the moles of base delivered when analyzing the impure KPH sample.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[n_{\text{NaOH}} = V_{NaOH} \times  M_\text{NaOH}\]

&lt;p&gt;where \(V_{\text{NaOH}}\) is the volume of NaOH in liters (L) to reach the endpoint for impure KHP titration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the moles of KHP using the stoichiometric ratio for the reaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[n_{\text{KHP}} = n_\text{NaOH} \times  \frac{1 \text{ mol KHP }}{ 1 \text{ mol NaOH }}\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the mass of KHP in impure sample.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[m_\text{KHP} =  n_{\text{KHP}} ( 204.2212 \text{ g/mol})\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the mass percent of KHP in impure sample.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[\text{mass % KHP} = \frac{m_\text{KHP}}{ m_\text{impure sample}} \times 100\%\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the average mass percent KHP and its standard deviation. Report the unknown number of the sample as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Print out pages 7-11 of the lab manual and respond to all prompts in a clearly written and well-organized manner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentation matters; sloppy and illegible work will not score well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your goal is to use the space provided to communicate your understanding of this experiment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scan and upload your work as a single PDF file by its deadline. You do not need to upload an Excel file for this experiment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should review the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Lab Report Guidelines&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sample General Chemistry Lab Report&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Appendix E&lt;/code&gt; on D2L while writing to ensure that your drafts are correctly formatted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;having-double-burette-readings-for-a-trial&quot;&gt;Having double burette readings for a trial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was wondering why each trial had two initial burette volumes and two final burette volumes instead of just one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the burette is to be refilled before the titration ends, you would have two readings of initial and final values. Another reason could be if you are delivering more than 50 mL volume. You would just sum the amount delivered for each reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-mermaid&quot;&gt;  graph LR;
    A[Is the assignment for the KHP Titration Experiment graded as a team?]
    B[Which sections are graded by the instructor?]
    C[Which sections are graded by the teaching assistant?]

    B1[Proofreading and General Formatting]
    B2[Average NaOH concentration and Standard Deviation]
    B3[Average %KHP and Standard Deviation]
    B4[Discussion Questions]

    C1[Prelab Assignment]
    C2[Postlab Quiz]
    C3[Tables 1 and 2]
    C4[Sample Calculations]

    A--yes--&amp;gt;B;
    A--yes--&amp;gt;C;
    B--&amp;gt;B1;
    B--&amp;gt;B2;
    B--&amp;gt;B3;
    B--&amp;gt;B4;

    C--&amp;gt;C1;
    C--&amp;gt;C2;
    C--&amp;gt;C3;
    C--&amp;gt;C4;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions regarding your scores, please let &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mkahveci@depaul.edu&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; or your &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brownt1129@gmail.com&quot;&gt;TA&lt;/a&gt; know.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="SSQ20 CHE 139" /><summary type="html">Goals, assignments, and Q&amp;As about the KHP Titration Experiment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Qualitative Analysis of Anions Experiment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/eml" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Qualitative Analysis of Anions Experiment" /><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/eml</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/eml">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button button--outline-success button--pill button--xs&quot; href=&quot;/tpv&quot;&gt;CHE 139&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext success highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Experiment 3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#goals&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#assignment&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#qas&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lab-notebook-pages&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lab-notebook-pages&quot;&gt;Lab notebook pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#team-grading&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis of known solutions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For this experiment, you will first test a series of known samples, each containing a particular anion, according to the prescribed test for it and record your observations.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Download the lab notebook from the course web page, and take notes  while watching the lab video recording. So, you will rely on your careful observations and own notes. This page will not be uploaded, it is for self-study only.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lab manual has enough details for preparing the sample test solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis of unknown solutions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You will then carry out the same analysis for two unknown samples, one from each batch of unknowns (i.e., NA #, NB #).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using the figure below, determine the unknown sample.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do not forget to note the unknown number in your lab report.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-mermaid&quot;&gt;  graph TD;
    A[Unknown]
    B[Chloride test]
    C1[If bubbles are present]
    C2[If neither bubbles nor precipitate is present]
    C3[If precipitate is present]
    D1[Unknown contains carbonade]
    D2[Carry on to sulfate, phophate, acetate, and nirate tests]
    D3[Carry on bromide, iodide, thiocyanate, and sulfide tests]
    A--&amp;gt;B;
    B--&amp;gt;C1;
    B--&amp;gt;C2;
    B--&amp;gt;C3;
    C1--yes--&amp;gt;D1;
    C2--yes--&amp;gt;D2;
    C3--yes--&amp;gt;D3;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the lab notebook from the course web page and fill it up while watching the demo video for the experiment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the data set and do the data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You must upload a PDF file of &lt;strong&gt;partial lab report&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should review the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Lab Report Guidelines&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sample General Chemistry Lab Report&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Appendix E&lt;/code&gt; on D2L while writing to ensure that your drafts are correctly formatted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lab-notebook-pages&quot;&gt;Lab notebook pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I see in the Lab 3 instructions on your website that the lab notebook pages are used to collect the observations necessary to transfer them to the main data table in the partial lab report, would you like us to submit that file with the notebook page as well or will just the PDF of the lab report suffice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just the PDF of the lab report, with the required observations tables, is sufficient. The file for lab notebook pages is posted for your own use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-mermaid&quot;&gt;  graph LR;
    A[Is the assignment for the Qualitative Analysis of Anions Experiment graded as a team?]
    B[Which sections are graded by the instructor?]
    C[Which sections are graded by the teaching assistant?]

    B1[Overall Clarity and Flow]
    B2[Abstract]
    B3[Results]
    B4[Results Table for Known Samples]
    B5[Unknown Identification]
    B6[Discussion Questions]

    C1[Procedure]
    C2[Table Formatting]
    C3[Prelab Assignment]
    C4[Postlab Quiz]

    A--yes--&amp;gt;B;
    A--yes--&amp;gt;C;
    B--&amp;gt;B1;
    B--&amp;gt;B2;
    B--&amp;gt;B3;
    B--&amp;gt;B4;
    B--&amp;gt;B5;
    B--&amp;gt;B6;

    C--&amp;gt;C1;
    C--&amp;gt;C2;
    C--&amp;gt;C3;
    C--&amp;gt;C4;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions regarding your scores, please let &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mkahveci@depaul.edu&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; or your &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brownt1129@gmail.com&quot;&gt;TA&lt;/a&gt; know.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="SSQ20 CHE 139" /><summary type="html">Goals, assignments, and Q&amp;As about the Qualitative Analysis of Anions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Iodine Clock Experiment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ykf" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Iodine Clock Experiment" /><published>2020-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ykf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ykf">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button button--outline-success button--pill button--xs&quot; href=&quot;/tpv&quot;&gt;CHE 139&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext success highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Experiment 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#goals&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#assignment&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#qas&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#concentrations-of-the-stock-solutions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-concentrations-of-the-stock-solutions&quot;&gt;Concentrations of the stock solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#calculating-the-initial-concentrations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-calculating-the-initial-concentrations&quot;&gt;Calculating the initial concentrations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#team-grading&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Determine the general rate law for a chemical reaction by calculating the reaction rate for various concentrations of reactants.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using the concentrations listed on the reagent bottles and the volumes in Table 2, calculate the diluted concentrations for each species using&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:dilution}
  M_2 = \frac{M_1V_1}{V_2}
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate the reaction rate for each trial using the diluted concentration of thiosulfate and the time (in seconds) it took for the blue complex to appear, using&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[\text{rate} = \frac{1}{2} \frac{[S_2O_3^{2-}]_i}{\Delta t}\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The partial order of each reactant will be found by comparing different rates and sets of concentrations to one another, yielding the experimental rate law for this specific reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use the method of initial rates and logarithms to calculate the partial order of each reactant for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; set of runs separately. e.g. The ratio of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run 2&lt;/code&gt; over &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run 1&lt;/code&gt; gives:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}\label{eq:rateratios}
 \frac{\text{rate}_2}{\text{rate}_1}  = \frac{ k [H^{+}]^x_2 [H_2O_2^{+}]^y_2 [I^{-}]^z_2}
    {k [H^{+}]^x_1 [^{+}]^y_1 [I^{-}]^z_1}
    = 
    \Big( \frac{[I^{-}]_2}
    { [I^{-}]_1} \Big)^z
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where \(z\) can be found by&lt;/p&gt;

\[z = \frac{\log \frac{\text{rate}_2}{\text{rate}_1} }{ \log \frac{[I^{-}]_2}
    { [I^{-}]_1} }\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This process is then repeated until all of the partial orders in the rate law are determined. The average partial orders should be listed to the same number of significant figures as the individual trial partial orders.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Calculate the rate constant at that temperature using the rate and concentration data from any run&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[k = \frac{\text{rate}}{[H^{+}]^x [H_2O_2^{+}]^y [I^{-}]^z }\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;\(k\) value should be calculated for each run, which means 4 runs \(\times\) 2 trials \(= 8\) different \(k\) values are calculated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Report average \(k\) constant \(\pm\) standard deviation, following the rules for significant figures.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch the demo video for the experiment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the data set and do the data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload the &lt;strong&gt;partial lab report&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/code&gt; format:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a deviation for the summer session only.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Include the following sections: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Procedures&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Data Table&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Experimental Rate Law&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/code&gt; (not a full discussion section; just itemize and answer the questions.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You don’t need to include sample calculations in the &lt;strong&gt;partial report&lt;/strong&gt; (it is in Excel only), don’t need to write narrative explaining data tables and calculations.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload all calculations and data tables in an MS Excel file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should review the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Lab Report Guidelines&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sample General Chemistry Lab Report&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Appendix E&lt;/code&gt; on D2L while writing to ensure that your drafts are correctly formatted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;concentrations-of-the-stock-solutions&quot;&gt;Concentrations of the stock solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was only given the concentration for \([H^+]\). However I believe that I need the stock concentrations of the other reactants as well in order to be able to calculate the diluted concentration of thiosulfite. Is there something that I am missing about this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\([H^+]\) concentration was given for some data sets by mistake. These affected data sets have been updated. Please re-download your data set and assume that the stock solutions are exactly prepared in the suggested values in Table 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 1. The concentrations of stock solutions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hydrochloric acid&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.0500 M&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hydrogen peroxide&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.5000 M&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Potassium iodide&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.0500 M&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sodium thiosulfate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.0100 M&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calculating-the-initial-concentrations&quot;&gt;Calculating the initial concentrations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re supposed to calculate \(M_2\) using data from Table 2. I’m not sure which volume to use with regards to runs since they change for different runs. Do I need to find \(M_2\) of all reactants for all 4 runs? Or do I just need to find \(M_2\) for a specific run?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the stock concentrations listed in Table 1 and the volumes in Table 2, calculate the diluted concentrations for each species by plugging in the values to Equation \ref{eq:dilution}. These calculated concentrations are known as initial concentrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/ykf/1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 450px;&quot; alt=&quot;kahveci group&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the intial concentration of hydrogen peroxide Run 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\(M_{H_2O_2} = \frac{(0.5000 \text{ M}))(10.00 \text{ mL})}{50.00 \text{ mL}} = 0.1000 \text{ M}\) (4 sig. figs.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Run 1, you will do this calculation for all species across the line. These values are the initial concentrations for Run 1. Repeat this calculation for all 4 runs and plug into Equation \ref{eq:rateratios} to find the partial orders of \(x\), \(y\), and \(z\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that you are expected to make an Excel table and do all of these individual calculations by using Excel functions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-mermaid&quot;&gt;  graph LR;
    A[Is the assignment for the Iodine Clock Experiment graded as a team?]
    B[Which sections are graded by the instructor?]
    C[Which sections are graded by the teaching assistant?]

    B1[Overall Clarity and Flow]
    B2[Abstract]
    B3[Results]
    B4[Discussion]
    B5[Proofreading and General Formatting]
    B6[Experimental Rate Law]
    B7[Discussion Questions]

    C1[Procedure]
    C2[Table Formatting]
    C3[Prelab Assignment]
    C4[Postlab Quiz]
    C5[Data Table]
    C6[Average Rate Constant]
    C7[Excel Calculations]

    A--yes--&amp;gt;B;
    A--yes--&amp;gt;C;
    B--&amp;gt;B1;
    B--&amp;gt;B2;
    B--&amp;gt;B3;
    B--&amp;gt;B4;
    B--&amp;gt;B5;
    B--&amp;gt;B6;
    B--&amp;gt;B7;

    C--&amp;gt;C1;
    C--&amp;gt;C2;
    C--&amp;gt;C3;
    C--&amp;gt;C4;
    C--&amp;gt;C5;
    C--&amp;gt;C6;
    C--&amp;gt;C7;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions regarding your scores, please let &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mkahveci@depaul.edu&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; or your &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brownt1129@gmail.com&quot;&gt;TA&lt;/a&gt; know.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="SSQ20 CHE 139" /><summary type="html">Goals, assignments, and Q&amp;As about the Iodine Clock Experiment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Raoult’s Law Experiment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nzx" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Raoult's Law Experiment" /><published>2020-07-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nzx</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nzx">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button button--outline-success button--pill button--xs&quot; href=&quot;/tpv&quot;&gt;CHE 139&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext success highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Experiment 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#goals&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#assignment&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#qas&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-area-values-for-the-pure-substances&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-area-values-for-the-pure-substances&quot;&gt;The area values for the pure substances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prepostlab-quizzes&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-prepostlab-quizzes&quot;&gt;Pre/postlab quizzes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#access-to-the-datasets&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-access-to-the-datasets&quot;&gt;Access to the datasets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-data-for-the-worksheet&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-data-for-the-worksheet&quot;&gt;The data for the worksheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-data-for-the-excel-file&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-data-for-the-excel-file&quot;&gt;The data for the Excel file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-worksheet&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-worksheet&quot;&gt;The worksheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#using-the-online-version-of-ms-office-and-a-chromebook&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-using-the-online-version-of-ms-office-and-a-chromebook&quot;&gt;Using the online version of MS Office and a Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#assessment&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-assessment&quot;&gt;Assessment&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#misconceptions&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-misconceptions&quot;&gt;Misconceptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#formatting-issues&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-formatting-issues&quot;&gt;Formatting issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#issues-with-calculations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-issues-with-calculations&quot;&gt;Issues with calculations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#team-grading&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#feedback&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determine the moles of each pure liquid per unit area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[n_A = A_{i,l} \frac{V_l \rho_i}{M_i A^0_{i,l}}\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determine the mole fraction of component A in the liquid phase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[\chi_A^l = \frac{n_A}{n_{\text{total}}}\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determine the partial pressure of each component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

\[P_{i,v} = A_{i,v} \frac{P^0_i}{A^0_{i,v}}\]

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generate the Raoult’s law plot (see Figure 1 in the manual)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment&quot;&gt;Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch the Excel workshop video for calculations and plotting expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the students spreadsheet for the workshop and do step by step calculations in the workshop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the data set and do the same analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload the Worksheet in PDF format (download the template as MS Word file and fill it out by following the instructions).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload all calculations and data tables in an MS Excel file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qas&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;As&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-area-values-for-the-pure-substances&quot;&gt;The area values for the pure substances&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I noticed that we did not have the area (pA.s) values for the pure substances. This value is necessary in order to begin calculations on the rest of the data. I have watched the lab introduction videos as well as your excel tutorial but I could not find this information and am hoping for some guidance to point me in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These values can be extracted from the Liquid data (the first table) and Gas data (the second table) separately. So, we will read this information as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When Part A equals to 1.0, it is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pure pentane&lt;/code&gt;. Pure pentane has both liquid and gas phases.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Liquid area: $ 5.10 \times 10^4 ~\text{pA.s} $&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gas area: $ 6.19 \times 10^4 ~\text{pA.s} $&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When Part A equals to 0.0, it is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pure hexane&lt;/code&gt;. Pure hexane has both liquid and gas phases.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Liquid area: $ 6.57 \times 10^4 ~\text{pA.s} $&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gas area: $ 2.82 \times 10^4 ~\text{pA.s} $&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/blog/nzx/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-1&quot; class=&quot;border&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prepostlab-quizzes&quot;&gt;Pre/postlab quizzes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I just completed the post lab quiz for lab 1 but it doesn’t let me see which questions I answered incorrectly. Is there any way you can turn this setting on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was just wondering how I can check what 2 answers I got wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These quizzes are set for unlimited attempts because 70% or higher is needed to continue the next steps. Therefore, the feedback functionality is limited on them. You would not see which questions were answered incorrectly in a previous attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;access-to-the-datasets&quot;&gt;Access to the datasets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have completed to pre-lab, post-lab, and lab videos for Lab 1. Can I have access to the data now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the completion of postlab quiz with 70% or higher grade, you are allowed to download the data sets assigned to you. You may need to refresh your browser to enable the hyperlink for &lt;a href=&quot;https://d2l.depaul.edu/d2l/le/content/761098/viewContent/6757299/View&quot;&gt;Experiment 1 Raoult’s Law Data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-data-for-the-worksheet&quot;&gt;The data for the worksheet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What data do I use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worksheet should be completed by using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://d2l.depaul.edu/d2l/le/content/761098/viewContent/6757299/View&quot;&gt;Experiment 1 Raoult’s Law Data&lt;/a&gt; dataset. This data set belongs to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;hexane&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;heptane&lt;/code&gt; mixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-data-for-the-excel-file&quot;&gt;The data for the Excel file&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What data do I use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://d2l.depaul.edu/d2l/le/content/761098/viewContent/6757287/View&quot;&gt;rubric&lt;/a&gt; and unlike the worksheet, your Excel file should include the analyses of both data sets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DCM&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;acetone&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pentane&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;hexane&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to choose and report one of the data sets in the worksheet. Please make sure that you indicate which data set you chose by marking the appropriate checkbox in the worksheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d2l.depaul.edu/d2l/le/content/761098/viewContent/6757294/View&quot;&gt;Experiment 1 Raoult’s Law Students&lt;/a&gt; dataset is for only practice. This data set is used for instructional video. Students should download the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DCM&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;acetone&lt;/code&gt; data and do the analysis while watching the video for the Excel workshop: &lt;a href=&quot;https://d2l.depaul.edu/d2l/le/content/761098/viewContent/6757297/View&quot;&gt;Experiment 1 Raoult’s Law Excel Workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-worksheet&quot;&gt;The worksheet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is the assignment only a worksheet, no lab report?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. This experiment has only worksheet. You do not write a lab report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-the-online-version-of-ms-office-and-a-chromebook&quot;&gt;Using the online version of MS Office and a Chromebook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was wondering if you could assist me with making the graphs for Experiment 1… This is a very short video the issue I am running into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching the video, I see that you are using the online version of MS Office and a Chromebook. I have not tested Chromebook specifically but I am quite positive that you need a regular computer to complete this course assignments. Even an old laptop/desktop maybe more powerful than a Chromebook. You should download and install a copy of MS Office on your computer in order to fully follow my instructions to make graphs and calculations in Excel. Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://offices.depaul.edu/information-services/services/Software/Pages/Software-for-Personal-Computers.aspx&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; for students to obtain a free MS Office copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assessment&quot;&gt;Assessment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;misconceptions&quot;&gt;Misconceptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pentane and hexane can be considered dipole-dipole due to the both being dipolar molecules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do your research more carefully. How do you determine the polarity of a compound?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Raoult’s Law Plot is made with trendlines (linear fit function).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not correct. This plot has hypothetical diagonal lines in order to observe deviations from the ideal behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formatting-issues&quot;&gt;Formatting issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figures have gridlines.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We require no gridlines on the figures. Please review the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Lab Report Guidelines&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sample General Chemistry Lab Report&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figure titles are missing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ranges for the chart axis values are not properly constrained.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;e.g. Raoult’s Law Plot should be constrained as follows:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Pressure (torr) ranges from 0.0 to 514.0&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Mole fraction ranges from 0.0 to 1.0&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This way your data will be easily interpreted by looking at the graph.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Remember we use plots to summarize our data in visual manner, not to confuse us even more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;issues-with-calculations&quot;&gt;Issues with calculations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formulae are missing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Values are not properly plugged in with units.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculations are not shown step by step until the final result.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i.e. Writing a formula and a value as its final result do not suffice the requirement: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Include all of the steps necessary to obtain the correct value&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-grading&quot;&gt;Team grading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-mermaid&quot;&gt;  graph LR;
    A[Is the assignment for the Raoult's Law Experiment graded as a team?]
    B[Which sections are graded by the instructor?]
    C[Which sections are graded by the teaching assistant?]

    B1[Proofreading and General Formatting]
    B2[Prelab Assignment]
    B3[Lab Conduct]
    B4[Example Calculations]
    B5[Discussion Questions]

    C1[Figure Formatting]
    C2[Graph 1]
    C3[Graph 2]
    C4[Excel Calculations: Acetone and DCM]
    C5[Excel Calculations: Pentane and Hexane]

    A--yes--&amp;gt;B;
    A--yes--&amp;gt;C;
    B--&amp;gt;B1;
    B--&amp;gt;B2;
    B--&amp;gt;B3;
    B--&amp;gt;B4;
    B--&amp;gt;B5;
    C--&amp;gt;C1;
    C--&amp;gt;C2;
    C--&amp;gt;C3;
    C--&amp;gt;C4;
    C--&amp;gt;C5;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions regarding your scores, please let &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mkahveci@depaul.edu&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; or your &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brownt1129@gmail.com&quot;&gt;TA&lt;/a&gt; know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The PDF file you uploaded: annotations are highlighted with gray background and pink font.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E-Rubric: D2L will show the rubric with scores and any feedback provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="SSQ20 CHE 139" /><summary type="html">Goals, assignments, and Q&amp;As about the Raoult's Law Experiment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘Thank you’ from Andres</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fxb" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="'Thank you' from Andres" /><published>2020-06-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fxb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fxb">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On Jun 3, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Professor Kahveci,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I just wanted to extend a sincere thank you to you and the entire Chemistry department, including our TA’s, for your compassion and understanding during these turbulent times. With everything going on, we’ve all been under an unusual amount of mental stress and I’m sure that extends to the teaching staff as well, so I hope you’ve all been well. The content in this class is not easy to grasp, but without the efforts of the staff making this information so comprehensible considering the short notice of this transition, I’m sure things could have been much worse. Also, I have seen a lot of leeway being given throughout this quarter in regards to grading and submission of assignments, and for me personally that has taken some of the stress out of this transition to our remote learning experience this quarter. It’s for this alleviation that I thank you all.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Andres&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andres is taking General Chemistry II (lecture and lab) in Spring 2020. This email correspondence was posted with Andres’s written permission via email on 6/3/2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="My Students" /><summary type="html">I just wanted to extend a sincere thank you to you and the entire Chemistry department, including our TA’s, for your compassion and understanding during these turbulent times. With everything going on, we’ve all been under an unusual amount of mental stress and I’m sure that extends to the teaching staff as well, so I hope you’ve all been well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">D2L Submission Folder Setup with a Rubric</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ydt" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="D2L Submission Folder Setup with a Rubric" /><published>2020-04-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ydt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ydt">&lt;p&gt;This tutorial demonstrates how to set up a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Submission&lt;/code&gt; folder with commenting capabilities and with an associated rubric for assessment. The rubric will be tied to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Grades&lt;/code&gt; module so that the rubric-based assessment  is automatically translated to an associated grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new--folder-in-submissions-with-annotation-tools&quot;&gt;New  Folder in Submissions with Annotation Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Navigate to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Submissions&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;New Folder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RO8wz-Yk-zEWLY8T4hDW_MwijWkt9FZvRU3awtCO0ZnXzl8XchwhftRwUClP0NSB2CX1Ana9OcpNZRytc-3SxK1hYer3fm4SdjzSRZpWtYqKQjDk5cDtcpZAtDMYtMxvIf_8xpqOZ3k=w2400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A&lt;/code&gt;: Give a name to the folder. e.g. Lab 1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Grade Item&lt;/code&gt; from the dropdown list. You can add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;New Grade Item&lt;/code&gt;, if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Add Rubric&lt;/code&gt; button and select a rubric from the list. If you don’t see a rubric, you need to &lt;a href=&quot;/ydt#rubric&quot;&gt;import&lt;/a&gt; one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/E8GcpGqbGk4_0M193wpGcSw9EzSQMuU2RZP08AabWHpaaE6HdU2GpGTfAjxYczxZ8UpuYpGyTfhaikm8FLmHjv74HCo7fLfilRW9pOIyQixNO2ewg1wNo2220tD-jXWj3ci12Lu722Q=w2400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Annotation Tools&lt;/code&gt; is checked. This is very important if you want to open the files submitted (without downloading) and give feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rubric&quot;&gt;Importing a Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;method-1-copying-from-my-course&quot;&gt;Method 1: Copying from my Course&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may import rubrics like any other components in D2L. I will be posting rubrics for SQ20-CHE 133 and SQ20-CHE 135 this quarter. To import a rubric:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Course Administration&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Import Components&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Search for offering&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Type &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CHE_135_901_1050&lt;/code&gt; in the search box to import a rubric for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CHE 135&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Type &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CHE_133_303_1050&lt;/code&gt; in the search box to import a rubric for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CHE 133&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FtkR0eeILqBRZ8IjZwo04U1l7vRuj8r6ate0ceCsmr3VHHEsjSOMX54QVEZLLu5ZANGEm5UoURcm6hQi-tBdSLWN7qLRm3OoDiRhJCmPDzgNS63YmLcWinZjRiLzpw_4-0STtZ34j8Y=w2400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Select Components&lt;/code&gt; and then check &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Rubrics&lt;/code&gt; to import.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait for copying and done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;method-2-importing-as-an-external-zip-file&quot;&gt;Method 2: Importing as an External ZIP File&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is for those who cannot import from my course. Originally, I did not think this would be a problem but I was notified that it was not possible to import a component from my course unless you were enrolled as a TA or instructor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, grab the rubric file as a ZIP from the shared Box folder.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In this folder, navigate to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Online Rubrics to Import D2L&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Any of these files must be imported to D2L as a ZIP file. So, don’t unzip. Naming convention:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SQ20-CHE133-lab-1-online-rubric-to-import-as-ZIP-file.zip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SQ20-CHE135-lab-1-online-rubric-to-import-as-ZIP-file.zip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On D2L, go to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Course Administration&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Import Components&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Import Components&lt;/code&gt; (again as submenu) and select and upload the ZIP file you grabbed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait for copying and done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Online Teaching" /><summary type="html">This tutorial demonstrates how to set up a Submission folder with commenting capabilities and with as associated rubric for assessment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Low Cost Options for Document Cameras</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/esy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Low Cost Options for Document Cameras" /><published>2020-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/esy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/esy">&lt;p&gt;If you need to write equations, etc during a Zoom lecture, a low cost document camera is useful to have – you can select it as a source in Zoom. Here are a couple on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/IPEVO-Definition-Document-Camera-5-880-4-01-00/dp/B079DLTG9F/ref=sr_1_3?keywords=document+camera&amp;amp;qid=1584109725&amp;amp;sr=8-3&quot;&gt;$99 – IPEVO V4K Ultra High Definition 8MP USB Document Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Gooseneck-Bed-Phone-Holder-Mount/dp/B07S9JXQP2/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=document+camera+phone+hold&amp;amp;qid=1584108860&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;$16.99 - Gooseneck Bed Phone Holder Mount&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Online Teaching" /><summary type="html">If you need to write equations, etc during a Zoom lecture, a low cost document camera is useful to have – you can select it as a source in Zoom. Here are a couple on Amazon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tools</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/xiw" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tools" /><published>2020-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/xiw</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/xiw">&lt;p&gt;Useful tools for online teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://padlet.com/&quot;&gt;Padlet&lt;/a&gt; (free). You open a pad and then double click to add a “post-it” note.  There are different ways to format where all posts go in a line down the center or they can be anywhere (and then moved by the instructor or students if you give permission).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.powtoon.com/home/&quot;&gt;Powtoon&lt;/a&gt;. You can make animations, videos, and infographics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.powtoon.com/home/&quot;&gt;Screencastify&lt;/a&gt;. Make awesome videos and presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Murat Kahveci</name><email>mkahveci@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Online Teaching" /><summary type="html">Useful tools for online teaching.</summary></entry></feed>